ANUP PAWALE



anuppawale@yahoo.co.in



9762119502



Pune, India 411041



Bold Profile

EDUCATION

MBA, Finance Symbiosis International University, Pune January 2023

M.D., Accounting And Finance **University of Pune**, Pune June 2011

LANGUAGES

Marathi

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

Hindi

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

English

Advanced (C1)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Account Executive with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in GST, TDS, Internal Audit, Balance Sheet, Accounting, and Income Tax. Account receivable and account payable, US accounting, Payroll management, Profession tax, Employees PF, Strong sales professional graduated from Garware college of commerce.

WORK HISTORY

July 2023 - Current

Accelirate Softech Pvt Ltd. - Senior Accountant, Pune

- Payroll Management with TDS, PF, PT, PF, Leave and attendance management
- Cheking a Cash entries, Account payable and Journal entries and give them approval
- Preapartion of Accounts payable summery
- Preaparation of monthly financials
- Checking a GST Calculation and TDS calculation and preparation of Advance tax working
- · Reconcilation of Bank statement
- · Preapare budget and Fund estimation statement
- Work related with STPI and Softex return.
- Streamlined the financial reporting process by implementing new accounting software and automating tasks.
- Assisted in internal and external audits by preparing necessary documentation and responding to auditor inquiries.
- Provided timely and accurate financial reporting to senior management, enabling informed decision-making based on reliable data.
- Reconciled accounts and created documents for monthly closure procedures.
- Prepared monthly journal entries and reconciliations.

February 2022 - July 2023

Speedypay Pvt. Ltd - Senior Accountant, Pune

- Manage all the accounting, financial transaction By entering information in accounting software
- GST working and filing return
- (GSTR 3B and 1)
- Prepare a calculation of TDS working and filled to government
- Payroll Management
- Expenses check and approval
- Submission of form 16 A & 16 B
- Calculation of income tax

- Salary returns filing
- (ITR 1 & ITR 2 ITR 4S)
- · Prepare Cost center wise accounting
- Reconciliation of Bank Statement with Speedypay wallet database
- Work closely with auditors and Charted accountant during the audit process and help him up to the finalization of accounts
- Vendor management.

June 2015 - December 2021

Ellicium Solutions Pvt Ltd - Account Officer, Pune

- Handled day to day accounting process to drive Financial accuracy
- Filling of vouchers, invoices, documents etc
- · Working on US accounts in tally
- GST working and filing return
- (GSTR 3B and 1)
- Reconcile the GSTR-1 and GSTR 3B with Internal data for the purpose of annual audit
- Prepare Cost center wise accounting to know the client wise profitability
- Prepare a calculation of TDS working and filled to government
- Generate a form 16 A and B from traces and submit to employees
- Calculation of income tax and checking and approval of tax document of employees
- Perform calculation of leaves, bonus, and process payroll
- Investigate payroll variances and employee claim to resolve discrepancies and balance financial record
- Employee Provident Fund Management
- Approve employee's expenses and managed expenses reporting
- Calculate PT & PTRC Return filing
- Work closely with auditors and Charted accountant during the audit process and help him up to the yearly finalization of accounts
- Working on monthly finalization and MIS preparation
- Foreign remittance working, obtain FIRC and record transaction in accounting software and prepare a sheet on foreign gain and loss of transaction
- Pre requisites of Employees documentation for foreign work travel.

July 2014 - May 2015

e-Arth Accounts Finance & Management Consultants Pvt. Ltd. - Accountant, Pune

- Operation of accounts payable, accounts receivable, cash receipts, general ledger
- Filling of vouchers, invoices, documents etc
- ITR-1 form filling to Income tax & document verification
- Professional Tax working and Return filing (PTRC & PTEC)
- Service tax Working and Return Filing
- LBT Working and Return filing
- VAT Working & Return Filing
- C and H form working in excel.

April 2013 - June 2014

Palshikar consultant Pvt. Ltd - Account Assistant and Auditor, Pune

- Operation of accounts payable, accounts receivable, cash receipts, general ledger
- Filling of vouchers, invoices, documents etc
- · VAT Working & LBT working
- Preparation of P&L, Balance sheet (Finalization)
- Professional Tax working and Return filing (PTRC & PTEC).

November 2011 - February 2013

Bhide and Shah charted account - Accountant Assistant and Auditor

- Examine the accounting records and ensure the accuracy
- Filing of vouchers, invoices, documents etc
- VAT Audit & Sales Tax Audit
- Cash and Assets verification, Checking of Tenders
- Ledger and Bank Scrutiny
- Preparation of P&L, Balance sheet (Finalization)
- Preparation of Audit Report.

December 2008 - January 2009

Union Bank of India - Data Entry Operator, Pune

- Filing of loan forms on computer database
- Filing & Uploading loan forms on central clearing agency online
- Letter writing to bank customers
- · Asset verification of clients
- Final check of loan proposals.

SKILLS

Payroll Processing Financial Reporting
Foreign Currency Transactions Account Reconciliation
Budget Preparation Financial Controls

Forecasting Financial statement review

Audit preparation Expense Tracking
Audit management Decision-Making